export const quizQuestions_5 = {
  questions: [
    {
      question: 'What is a React component?',
      choices: ['A reusable piece of UI', 'A JavaScript function or class that returns HTML', 'A DOM element', 'A CSS stylesheet'],
      correctAnswer: 'A JavaScript function or class that returns HTML',
    },
    {
      question: 'How can you create a functional component in React?',
      choices: ['Using the class keyword', 'By extending React.Component', 'As a JavaScript function', 'By using the render() method'],
      correctAnswer: 'As a JavaScript function',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the purpose of props in React components?',
      choices: ['To manage component state', 'To handle user events', 'To pass data from parent to child components', 'To modify the DOM directly'],
      correctAnswer: 'To pass data from parent to child components',
    },
    {
      question: 'How do you define a stateful component in React?',
      choices: ['By using functional components', 'By using the setState() method', 'By passing props', 'By using class components'],
      correctAnswer: 'By using class components',
    },
    {
      question: 'What does the `setState()` method do in React components?',
      choices: ['Updates the component state and re-renders the component', 'Changes the component props', 'Creates a new component instance', 'Removes the component from the DOM'],
      correctAnswer: 'Updates the component state and re-renders the component',
    },
    {
      question: 'How can you render a React component within another component?',
      choices: ['Using props', 'By directly calling the component function', 'By using the render() method', 'By importing and using the component'],
      correctAnswer: 'By importing and using the component',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the significance of the key prop in React components?',
      choices: ['To identify each component uniquely in lists and optimize rendering', 'To style the components', 'To manage state changes', 'To define the order of components'],
      correctAnswer: 'To identify each component uniquely in lists and optimize rendering',
    },
    {
      question: 'Which method is used to handle user input in React components?',
      choices: ['handleChange()', 'handleUserInput()', 'onClick()', 'useState()'],
      correctAnswer: 'onChange()',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the purpose of the `prompt()` method in React?',
      choices: ['To display a dialog box to input data', 'To render components', 'To manage state', 'To create new components'],
      correctAnswer: 'To display a dialog box to input data',
    },
    {
      question: 'How can data from a prompt dialog be handled in a React component?',
      choices: ['By using event listeners', 'By directly assigning to state', 'By using props', 'By capturing the return value from prompt()'],
      correctAnswer: 'By capturing the return value from prompt()',
    },
  ],
};
